<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thicket N&#39;Thorn</title>
    <link>https://sligulli.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thicket N&#39;Thorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sligulli.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>zonnet</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/post/zonnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/post/zonnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seventh decade and still not so smart, what&lt;br /&gt;
does it mean to go out of my mind, as if&lt;br /&gt;
that were possible? Zenith, my second,&lt;br /&gt;
of which I is a shadow oftime over&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;shadowed (Picture this as concrete. Form&lt;br /&gt;
a mental image of this process), Zenith,&lt;br /&gt;
my mother, when all preconceptions turn&lt;br /&gt;
upside down. The cycle is more than a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;man, man wrong, as usual. To right whatever&lt;br /&gt;
rolls over simply occurs without the need&lt;br /&gt;
to consult calendar or clock. Heat and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;more heat, sometimes we sizzle, pop, and&lt;br /&gt;
explode. Never an organizational wizard,&lt;br /&gt;
what does it mean to seek inchoate arcana?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>papa beard</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/post/papabeard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/post/papabeard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Old guy snoozing supine beneath a stiff&lt;br /&gt;
westerly chill on a beach beyond the mouth&lt;br /&gt;
of the Hoh. Shades of grey highlight&lt;br /&gt;
his wizened complexion while ravens feast&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on his eyeballs. Supposing he dreams, he&amp;rsquo;s&lt;br /&gt;
astonished when waking and rubbing his&lt;br /&gt;
hollowed sockets. Blindly stumbling over&lt;br /&gt;
and beyond piled and long weathered tide&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stranded timber into the forest, his hand&lt;br /&gt;
touches usnea which he stuffs into the holes&lt;br /&gt;
where eyes once snuggled restoring luminous&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;imagery enhanced, eidetic inner depths and&lt;br /&gt;
distances coalescent exceeding anything&lt;br /&gt;
he previously may have ever imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plain</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/post/plain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/post/plain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As it is without, so it is within.&lt;br /&gt;
Where water meets land, land shall meet water.&lt;br /&gt;
Between earth and sky stands a two legged&lt;br /&gt;
speck. His thin path opens a trade route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water carries away the poisons he&lt;br /&gt;
makes until all water becomes deadly.&lt;br /&gt;
As it is without, so shall it be with&lt;br /&gt;
in. Plant life cleanses air and water. He&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cuts and burns trees that have managed to stand&lt;br /&gt;
for over five hundred years. He plugs&lt;br /&gt;
great rivers until those rivers run dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s better to stop here and sit.&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s best to sit and do nothing.&lt;br /&gt;
Allow heart to open to each instant enchant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cracker</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/post/cracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/post/cracker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To choose from a shrewd distribution of options,&lt;br /&gt;
overcrowding, nuclear meltdown, pestilence,&lt;br /&gt;
cyanide, bullet, wildfire, heat wave, or&lt;br /&gt;
flood would not be considered uncanny. A break&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the weather illuminates a gap between molecular bonds&lt;br /&gt;
and the impetus which corrodes the gastrointestinal&lt;br /&gt;
tractor which, likewise, rusts abandoned in the lower&lt;br /&gt;
left abdominal quadrant, Sigmoid, a funny name&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for the father of psychoanalysis, Sigmoid&lt;br /&gt;
Freud rather, not. Honestly, we know&lt;br /&gt;
better than that. Sunrise. Four old men converge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at the local municipal dog park. Three bring&lt;br /&gt;
their dogs, while another brings crackers to feed&lt;br /&gt;
the squirrels. The dogs lichen that guy and his crackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>colorado</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/post/colorado/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/post/colorado/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Colorado, stunningly cursed by the visual&lt;br /&gt;
effects it evokes in humans, is yet one&lt;br /&gt;
of many categorical impositions on an other&lt;br /&gt;
wise unbroken map. How did it come to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so stupidly square? Colorado could be said to be tall&lt;br /&gt;
but not tall enough to escape the distances&lt;br /&gt;
between the dull wit of its tracing, likewise,&lt;br /&gt;
the concrete nuances of who’s doing the taking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glassy eyed automatons boxed into triviality, this package&lt;br /&gt;
transcribes a peripheral indulgence wherein arrivals&lt;br /&gt;
conceptualize a tangle of crippled roadway, a damaged&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;matériel device. Wind through timber diminished in ice&lt;br /&gt;
and a vertical crag, where, and toward what end, does&lt;br /&gt;
one inscribe upon this breeding enormity a proprietary line?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>plant spirit</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/post/badplant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/post/badplant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At a depot between what is and what&lt;br /&gt;
isn&amp;rsquo;t breathing, a steady rhythm shall&lt;br /&gt;
suffice. Alone with a drum is all any&lt;br /&gt;
one needs to travel. Mismatched rattles, one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in each hand, matter and spirit carry&lt;br /&gt;
us to a good place. A steady rhythm&lt;br /&gt;
unwinds the tangle and rounds all awhirl.&lt;br /&gt;
Sometimes we move under, other times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;up. Life an illusion, Tobacco rips&lt;br /&gt;
a pinhole in the distant horizon&lt;br /&gt;
raising an approaching cloud ocher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pink Chevelle SS 454, brakes locked,&lt;br /&gt;
skids to a 360 stop, engine rumbling,&lt;br /&gt;
mere inches away, and waits for its rider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dreamtimejourneys.net/masks.html&#34;&gt;Gail&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>so-called &#39;&#39;bad&#39;&#39; plants</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/post/badplants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/post/badplants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey.&lt;br /&gt;
I admire bad plants.&lt;br /&gt;
I admire plants fallen into widespread disrepute &amp;amp; disfavor.&lt;br /&gt;
I admire plants branded as invasive, whether native or not.&lt;br /&gt;
I admire plant notoriety &amp;amp; those designated as illegal or even (gasp) evil.&lt;br /&gt;
I admire plants blamed for what invariably turns out to be willful human ignorance.&lt;br /&gt;
I admire plants blamed for what may, perhaps, turn out to be unintended human ignorance.&lt;br /&gt;
I admire plants blamed for what honestly turns out to be human misuse and abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire &amp;amp; respect dense vegetal tangles &amp;amp; thorny resilience.&lt;br /&gt;
I applaud plants run amok in an effort to fill, protect, &amp;amp; heal areas damaged by human design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey.&lt;br /&gt;
The best way to enter an impenetrable thicket is to ask for permission.&lt;br /&gt;
Leave the machete to rust.&lt;br /&gt;
The best way to enter an impenetrable thicket is to ask for permission slip in &amp;amp; sit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reading list</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/post/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/post/books/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I decided to put together a personal reading list with (if I feel the urge) commentary. If I don&amp;rsquo;t consider a book, or essay, or poem worth the trouble, it won&amp;rsquo;t be found it here. Nevertheless, this is a list I cannot ever hope to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;emsp-emsp-acupuncture-related-material&#34;&gt;&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;acupuncture related material&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fourth Uncle in the Mountain&lt;/em&gt; by Quang Van Nguyen &amp;amp; Marjorie Pivar&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Atlas of Chinese Tongue Diagnosis&lt;/em&gt; by Barbara Kirschbaum&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are needles used more than once?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/cleanneedlez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/cleanneedlez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/images/great thoroughfare.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Needles come in sterile packaging and are disposed of in a sharps container when removed. Every practitioner who holds an acupuncture license has been thoroughly trained and tested in clean needle technique.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do I have to take off my clothes?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/doihavetotakeoffmyclothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/doihavetotakeoffmyclothes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No! You do not necessarily have to take off your clothes. However, if you want cupping, gua sha, or moxa it may be easier to either move loose clothing or remove a shirt and cover up under a sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, almost all acupuncture treatments are conducted on people in the supine (face-up) position, and the most commonly used points are on the arms, hands, legs, and feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So all you need to do is wear loose clothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help with a shoulder problem (for example), access to that area might help. But long sleeves still won&amp;rsquo;t generally prevent acupuncture from facilitating improvement with shoulder problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those tight tight elastic pants so popular now do occasionally limit access some excellent points, but we can work around that also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, loose clothing is best; circulation of blood and qi all the way down into the toes and fingertips is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice of acupuncture points is fluid and adaptive. We can always find work-around or alternative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t worry if you haven’t had time to shave your legs for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t judge your bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, we have bodies too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we simply want to help you feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does acupuncture hurt?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/doesithurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/doesithurt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Odd as it may sound, acupuncture is a gentle practice, and needles can be adjusted to accomodate varying individual sensitivities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture needles are solid, flexible, and quite thin. Acupuncture is considerably different than getting a shot with a fat and hollow hypodermic syringe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most commonly people feel a tiny and brief prick when needles are inserted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be followed by an ache, a quick electrical shock which subsides, a slight itch, or merely a tingle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often express surprise when they cannot feel a needle at all, but some acupuncture points may provoke a strong reflex sensation. This arrival of qi (chee) often occurs suddenly, after which it gradually calms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therapeutically, the arrival and movement of qi is a positive signal and an indication of vitality and positive life force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since acupuncture needles are used to move energy, first timers frequently tune into that movement with amazement and curiousity. Once the needles are in, most people relax and take a well deserved and much needed nap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQs</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/doihavetotakeoffmyclothes&#34;&gt;Do I have to take off my clothes?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/doesithurt&#34;&gt;Does acupuncture hurt?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/cleanneedlez&#34;&gt;Are needles used more than once?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/frequency&#34;&gt;How often should I come in for treatments?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/whatneedlesdo&#34;&gt;What do acupuncture needles do?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/whatisca&#34;&gt;What is community acupuncture?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/payment&#34;&gt;What should I pay?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/whyabinth&#34;&gt;Why the name Thicket N&amp;rsquo;Thorn?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hours / Fees</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/page/hours-fees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/page/hours-fees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; Monday &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;   10:00 - 3:00&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; Wednesday &amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; 12:00 - 6:30&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; Friday  &amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;   12:00 - 6:30&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; Saturday &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; 10:00 - 2:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;​​Fees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; $10 first time paperwork fee&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; $15-40 / Community Acupuncture&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; Free phone consultations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book Now&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;emsp;&amp;emsp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.shedul.com/online_bookings/thicket-n-thorn-community-acupuncture-tektawrm&#34;&gt;Save me a seat!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How often should I come in for treatments?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/frequency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/frequency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Individual needs vary; acupuncture works cumulatively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More frequent the treatments tend to result in more positive outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture is a PROCESS. How many times have you picked up a prescription for 1 pill?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In China, it is common for people to come for treatments 6 days a week with 2 off for 6-8 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people do not need that much acupuncture. But a series of 1-3 treatments per week for several weeks is generally recommended. This is how the sliding scale fee system allows for more effective outcomes than private treatments at $75 per visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, a lot of us are like an old guitar string. We can get that string in tune, but it doesn’t stay that way for long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people find that treatments once per week or twice per month work wonders as a tune-up or preventive strategy, and many simply learn to sense when an acpuncture treatment is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do acupuncture needles do?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/whatneedlesdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/page/faqs/whatneedlesdo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am often asked, “what do acupuncture needles do?” The simple answer is that the needles move qi or energy in an effort to restore balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It helps to consider observations taken from nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we visualize sitting or standing next to a pond on a windless day, the surface of the water appears like a glass mirror; detailed relections are vivid and, under ideal conditions, exact. If a stone is tossed into the water, ripples reverberate across the entire surface of the pond. The stone initiates an energetic response which can be seen as movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what acupuncture needles do. They set off energetic reverberations throughout the body. This is why headaches can be successfully treated with points on the feet, or pain on the plantar surface of the left heel can be treated successfully with needles inserted into the base of the palm on the right hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qi moves through everything. Qi makes the exponential multiplicities of life possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it is without, so it is within. We are not separate from the places through which we move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not separate from that which moves through us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/images/waldenpond.JPG#center&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>