<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Faqs on Thicket N&#39;Thorn</title>
    <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Faqs on Thicket N&#39;Thorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Are needles used more than once?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/cleanneedlez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/cleanneedlez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/images/great thoroughfare.jpg#center&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Needles come in sterile packaging and are disposed of in a sharps container when removed. Every practitioner who holds an acupuncture license has been thoroughly trained and tested in clean needle technique.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do I have to take off my clothes?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/doihavetotakeoffmyclothes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/doihavetotakeoffmyclothes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No! You do not necessarily have to take off your clothes. However, if you want cupping, gua sha, or moxa it may be easier to either move loose clothing or remove a shirt and cover up under a sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, almost all acupuncture treatments are conducted on people in the supine (face-up) position, and the most commonly used points are on the arms, hands, legs, and feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So all you need to do is wear loose clothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help with a shoulder problem (for example), access to that area might help. But long sleeves still won&amp;rsquo;t generally prevent acupuncture from facilitating improvement with shoulder problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those tight tight elastic pants so popular now do occasionally limit access some excellent points, but we can work around that also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, loose clothing is best; circulation of blood and qi all the way down into the toes and fingertips is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice of acupuncture points is fluid and adaptive. We can always find work-around or alternative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t worry if you haven’t had time to shave your legs for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t judge your bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, we have bodies too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we simply want to help you feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does acupuncture hurt?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/doesithurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/doesithurt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Odd as it may sound, acupuncture is a gentle practice, and needles can be adjusted to accomodate varying individual sensitivities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture needles are solid, flexible, and quite thin. Acupuncture is considerably different than getting a shot with a fat and hollow hypodermic syringe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most commonly people feel a tiny and brief prick when needles are inserted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might be followed by an ache, a quick electrical shock which subsides, a slight itch, or merely a tingle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often express surprise when they cannot feel a needle at all, but some acupuncture points may provoke a strong reflex sensation. This arrival of qi (chee) often occurs suddenly, after which it gradually calms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therapeutically, the arrival and movement of qi is a positive signal and an indication of vitality and positive life force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since acupuncture needles are used to move energy, first timers frequently tune into that movement with amazement and curiousity. Once the needles are in, most people relax and take a well deserved and much needed nap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How often should I come in for treatments?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/frequency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/frequency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Individual needs vary; acupuncture works cumulatively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More frequent the treatments tend to result in more positive outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture is a PROCESS. How many times have you picked up a prescription for 1 pill?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In China, it is common for people to come for treatments 6 days a week with 2 off for 6-8 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people do not need that much acupuncture. But a series of 1-3 treatments per week for several weeks is generally recommended. This is how the sliding scale fee system allows for more effective outcomes than private treatments at $75 per visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, a lot of us are like an old guitar string. We can get that string in tune, but it doesn’t stay that way for long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people find that treatments once per week or twice per month work wonders as a tune-up or preventive strategy, and many simply learn to sense when an acpuncture treatment is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do acupuncture needles do?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/whatneedlesdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/whatneedlesdo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am often asked, “what do acupuncture needles do?” The simple answer is that the needles move qi or energy in an effort to restore balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It helps to consider observations taken from nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we visualize sitting or standing next to a pond on a windless day, the surface of the water appears like a glass mirror; detailed relections are vivid and, under ideal conditions, exact. If a stone is tossed into the water, ripples reverberate across the entire surface of the pond. The stone initiates an energetic response which can be seen as movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what acupuncture needles do. They set off energetic reverberations throughout the body. This is why headaches can be successfully treated with points on the feet, or pain on the plantar surface of the left heel can be treated successfully with needles inserted into the base of the palm on the right hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qi moves through everything. Qi makes the exponential multiplicities of life possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it is without, so it is within. We are not separate from the places through which we move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not separate from that which moves through us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/images/waldenpond.JPG#center&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is community acupuncture?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/whatisca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/whatisca/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-community-acupuncture&#34;&gt;What is community acupuncture?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community acupuncture is a business model where treatments take place in a common room as opposed to one which is private. The advantage of this setup allows the business to charge lower fees by providing access to more people to receive treatments at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who may feel uncomfortable talking about personal information in an open clinic setting, free phone consultations are available at eight-two-eight four-five-zero three-seven-two-one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should I pay?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/payment/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-should-i-pay-or-how-does-the-sliding-scale-work&#34;&gt;What should I pay, or how does the sliding scale work?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A primary incentive to set up a sliding scale payment system is to provide acupuncture for those who otherwise cannot afford it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, it also extends the possibilty that people can receive treatments more frequently if necessary or desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a $15-40 sliding scale, for instance, someone whose budget is limits her to $60 per week for acupuncture is not restricted to coming in for one treatment per week. She could actually come in 2, 3, or 4 times if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing an opportunity for people to come more frequently increases the odds that people will have positive results that last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what amount you choose to pay, by receiving acupuncture at Thicket N&amp;rsquo;Thorn, you are supporting health care for others in the community while providing a sustainable income for your practitioner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the name Thicket N&#39;Thorn?</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/whyabinth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/faqs/whyabinth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sligulli.github.io/images/thistle.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doubt arises regarding the wisdom of naming an acupuncture clinic Thicket N&amp;rsquo;Thorn while featuring a picture of a cactus with especially wicked looking spines. So I waver between that and some other epithet more cliché or bland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lifelong fascination with figurative immediacy, however, tends to favor an elemental astonishment arising from  riskier juxtapositions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also savor the music, the voiced TH dipthongs, the assonance, the intervening fricative, the vernacular contraction jamming together &amp;ldquo;and thorn&amp;rdquo; as it may be commonly spoken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture is much kinder than being speared by a cactus or snagged by a rose, although roses and many cactuses do have medicinal value. Likewise, this hazard does not detract from either the physical or symbolic elegance of such pointy plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture is, nonetheless, a complex medicine long steeped in metaphorical resonance. As one of my acupuncture friends puts it, &amp;ldquo;acupuncture is the poetry of the body.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I hope the home page doesn&amp;rsquo;t scare anyone away, and I promise not to thrash anyone with a thistle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~~~//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>