<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflections on Thicket N&#39;Thorn</title>
    <link>https://sligulli.github.io/reflections/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflections on Thicket N&#39;Thorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://sligulli.github.io/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>4th Uncle in the Mountain - Recommended Reading</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/reflections/4thUncle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/reflections/4thUncle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fourth Uncle in the Mountain&lt;/em&gt; by Quang Van Nguyen &amp;amp; Marjorie Pivar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is Quang Van Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s autobiography. It begins when he was abandoned by his parents at the foot of a flagpole in a bustling market at dawn someplace in the Mekong Delta in Vietnam. (It&amp;rsquo;s been awhile since I read the book, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth reading again.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This abandonment occurred during the period following the second world war when the French were reasserting their colonial dominance over the Vietnamese people who were widely opposed to this French effort. As they saw it, they had finally ousted the Japanese oppressors, and now they had to do the same with the French and, then again later, the US CIA and military. Most of us know something about this, and those of us who are old enough probably know than we&amp;rsquo;d otherwise wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, his father was a Buddhist monk, and this meant he was a primary target of the French authorities. His parents were therefore fleeing for their lives. This was why he was left at the foot of the flagpole immediately preceding the daily requirement of everyone to cease bartering and face the raising of the French flag as &amp;ldquo;The Internationale&amp;rdquo; (ironically) blasted over the marketplace. In other words, his parents knew he&amp;rsquo;d be found and cared for, as turned out to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book then follows his development, education, and truancy up to and beyond how he learned acupuncture and herbalism from his adopted father who was a traveling doctor throughout the delta all while war raged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marjorie Pivar met him in Vermont on an herb walk and was astounded at the depth of his knowledge regarding edible and medicinal used of plants and mushrooms in the area given that he hadn&amp;rsquo;t lived there long at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So together they agreed to write his story, and an excellent story it is. But I suggest you find out for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tongue Diagnosis - Recommended Reading</title>
      <link>https://sligulli.github.io/reflections/tongue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sligulli.github.io/reflections/tongue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atlas of Chinese Tongue Diagnosis&lt;/em&gt; by Barbara Kirschbaum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the best reference book on tongue diagnosis, and anyone should be able to begin using this book to learn this excellent diagnostic technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The photos of tongues are consistent and sharp, while the combination of western and Chinese diagnostic terminology according to what each tongue shows deepens understanding into the the similarities and differences between the two modalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond merely providing an atlas of tongue pictures and descriptions, several in-depth case studies are also provided which correspond to changes on the tongue as health improves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>